So, now let's put this all together and study how to get
现在将这些组合到一起 研究一下如何根据各自的
these two matrices in the LDA model based on their respective dirichlet distributions.
狄利克雷分布获得 LDA 模型中的这两个矩阵
The rough idea is as we just saw,
大致方式就是我们看到的
the entries from the first matrix come from picking points in the distribution alpha.
第一个矩阵中的条目来自分布 α 中的点
The interest from the second matrix come from from picking points in distribution beta.
第二个矩阵的条目来自分布 β 中的点
The idea is to find the best locations of
目标是找到这些点的最佳位置
these points to get the best factorization of the matrix.
以便获得矩阵的最佳分解结果
The best locations of these points will give us precisely the topics we want.
这些点的最佳位置将使我们获得所需的主题
Let's generate some documents,
我们生成一些文档
in order to compare them with the originals.
以便与原始文档进行比较
We started with dirichlet distribution for topics alpha.
我们从主题 α 的狄利克雷分布开始
From here, we draw some points corresponding to all the documents.
然后选择与所有文档对应的一些点
Let's start by drawing one of them.
我们先选择其中一个点
This point will give some values for each of the three topics,
这个点将为三个主题分别提供一些值
which will generate a multivariate distribution theta.
生成多项分布 θ
This is the mixture of topics,
这是与文档 1 对应的
corresponding to document one.
主题混合结果
Now, let's generate some words for document one as follows.
现在为文档 1 生成一些单词
From theta, we draw some topics. How many topics?
我们从 θ 中选择一些主题 多少个主题呢？
This is a bit out of the scope,
这超出了这门课程的范畴
but the idea is that we'll have a Poisson variable to tell us how many.
原理是根据泊松变量判断选择多少个主题
Just think of yet another parameter in this model.
可以直接看作这个模型中的另一个参数
So, we draw some topics based on the probability is
我们根据这个分布提供的概率
given by this distribution, which means,
选择一些主题
we'll draw science with a 0.7 probability,
选择科学的概率是 0.7
politics with 0.2, and sports with 0.1.
政治是 0.2, 体育是 0.1
Now, we'll associate words to these topics.
现在将单词与这些主题相关联
How? Using the words dirichlet distribution beta.
如何关联？使用单词狄利克雷分布 β
In this distribution, we locate the topic somewhere,
在这个分布中 我们确定该主题在某个位置
and from each of these dots,
从每个点中
we obtain a distribution of the words,
获得由每个主题生成的
are generated by each of the topics.
单词的分布
For example, topic one science,
例如主题 1 科学
generates the word space with 0.4 probability.
生成单词 space 的概率是 0.4
Climate with 0.4, vote with 0.1,
生成 Climate 的概率是 0.4 生成 vote 的概率是 0.1
and rule with 0.1 probability.
生成 rule 的概率是 0.1
These distributions are called phi.
这些分布称为 Φ
Now, for each of the topics we've chosen,
对于所选的每个主题
we'll pick a word associated to it using the multivariate distribution phi.
我们将使用多元分布 Φ 选择与其相关的一个单词
For example, for the first topic we have science.
例如 第一个主题是科学
We look at the science row in the phi distribution and pick a word out there.
我们在 Φ 分布中查看科学所在行 并从中选择一个单词
For example, space.
例如 space
So, space is the first word in document one.
space 是文档 1 中的第一个单词
We do this for every one of these topics and
我们对每个主题执行这一流程
then generate words from our first generated document.
然后从第一个生成文档（称之为“虚假文档 1”）中
Let's call it "fake document one".
生成单词
We do this process again,
重复这一流程
drawing another point from the alpha distribution,
从 α 分布中选择另一个点
getting another multivariable distribution theta,
获得另一个多元分布 θ
which generates new topics which from beta
生成新的主题
generate new words and that's "fake document two".
并从 β 中生成新的单词 它是“虚假文档 2”
We go on and on, generating many documents.
一直持续下去 生成很多文档
Now, it's time to compare them with originals.
现在将这些文档与原始文档进行比较
What we'll do is we want to use maximum likelihood to figure out the arrangements
我们将使用最大似然率
of points which will give us the real articles with the highest probability.
找到获得真实文章概率最高的一系列点
In summary, here's what we're doing.
总结下具体流程
We have the two dirichlet distributions, alpha and beta.
我们有两个狄利克雷分布 α 和 β
From the distribution alpha,
我们从分布 α 中选择一些文档
we pick some documents and from distribution beta,
并从分布 β 中
we pick some topics.
选择一些主题
We use these two combined to create some fake articles.
将这两个相结合 创建虚假文章
Then we compare them to the real articles.
然后将这些虚假文章与真实文章比较
The probability of obtaining the real articles,
当然 获得真实文章的概率
of course is really small,
非常小
but there must be some arrangement of points in
但是 上方分布中肯定有一些点的组合
the above distributions that maximizes this probability.
能够最大化这个概率
Our goal is to find this arrangement of points and that will give us the topics.
我们的目标是找到这个点组合并获得主题
In the same way that we train many algorithms in machine learning,
就像训练机器学习中的很多算法一样
there will be an error that will tell us how
肯定有错误 可以告诉我们
far we are from generating the real articles.
与生成真实文章的偏差有多大
The error will back propagate all the way to the distributions,
该错误将反向传播到分布中
giving us a gradient that will tell us where to
获得一个梯度
move the points in order to reduce this error.
可以告诉我们向哪移动点 以便减小这个错误
So, we move the points as indicated and now we've obtained a slightly better model.
我们根据提示移动点 现在获得效果稍微好些的模型
Doing this repeatedly, will give us a good enough arrangement on the points.
重复这一流程将获得效果不错的点组合
Naturally, a good arrangement of the points will give us some topics.
通常 效果好的点组合将为我们提供一些主题
The dirichlet distribution alpha,
狄利克雷分布 α
will tell us what articles are associated to
将告诉我们哪些文章与这些主题相关
these topics and the dirichlet distribution beta,
狄利克雷分布 β
will tell us what words are associated to these topics.
将告诉我们哪些单词与这些主题相关
We can go a bit further and actually backpropagate the error,
我们可以进一步推理并反向传播错误
all the way to alpha and beta,
一直回到 α 和 β
obtaining not only better point arrangements but actually better distributions,
不仅获得效果更好的点组合 而且获得更好的分布
alpha and beta prime.
α’ 和 β’
That's it. That's how latent dirichlet analysis works.
就这样 这就是潜在狄利克雷分析的原理
If you want to understand the diagram and the paper, here it is.
如果你想了解论文中的图表 这就是该图表
All we need to know, what the alpha is the topics distribution.
我们只需知道 α 是主题分布
Beta is the words distribution, theta and phi,
β 是单词分布
are the multivariate distributions drawn from them,
θ 和 φ 是从这两个分布中获取的多元分布
Z are our topics and W,
z 是主题
are the documents obtained by combining these two.
w 是将这两个相结合后获得的文档